so now that we have seen an example of
memory ordering let's do a memory
ordering quiz let's say we have a load a
store another pair of floating store
let's say that all of the loads are
cache misses so what happens is in cycle
1 we begin executing this load and send
it to memory and it's gonna take 40
cycles for it to return a value so in
cycle 1 we send the request to memory in
cycle 41 we finally get the value and
now we have our r1 let's say that we are
doing stores and loads out of order so
although this store really cannot get
the value until cycle 41 at least we
proceed with this load so in cycle 2 we
send it to memory in cycle 42 we'll get
the value this store waits for that
value but this load is sent to memory in
cycle 3 and in cycle 43 it gets the
value now what happens in cycle 42 is
this store is finally done and then in
cycle 43 this store is done and in cycle
44 this cycle is done so overall we have
taken 44 cycles to do this but we have
been doing loads prematurely as far as
the stores are concerned because if this
r2 + 4 is equal to r3 + 0 then actually
this load should have waited so we
decided not to be totally safe and go
and then we are assuming that there will
be some recovery mechanism your task is
to figure out when is each of these
instructions sent to memory and when do
we get the result from memory and what's
the final cycle count if we do things in
order
so if loads and stores have to happen in